ivona.com 2015-12-29

# Privacy Policy | IVONA Text-to-Speech

### 1\. What information do we collect?

We may collect personal information from you relating both to your identity and personal preferences, including name and surname, address, e-mail address, phone number, login and password, name of the company you represent and NIP (tax identification) number. We will endeavor only to collect such information as is necessary for the below stated purpose for which we are collecting the information. For example, if you purchase our products, we will require your personal information so that we can send you your login and access key information, deliver your products and obtain payment.

There are a number of different ways that we may collect personal information from you:

_Communications from you_  
You may contact us providing your name and contact details and any other personal information contained in your message.

_Customer Support_  
You may contact us in respect of technical assistance you require in respect of our products or information that you would like to receive relating to our products.

_Email/Direct mail campaigns_  
From time to time we may contact you directly by mail, email or telephone informing you about upgrades, new products, promotions or special offers that you may be interested in or asking you for your opinion on our products and/or services. However, we refrain from sending unsolicited information to persons who have not given their consent.

_Newsletters_  
To those customers who gave us their consent we may send out newsletters providing them with articles and information which we believe may be of interest to them.

_Registration and Use of Website, Products & Services_

Upon registration, we may ask you to provide certain information so that we can provide you with service and information related to our website, products and services.

_Product Feedback_  
It is important for us to receive feedback from our customers and information on any features they would like to see in future products and services. We may, upon your consent, contact you to ask you about our products and also to inform you of upgrades, technical issues, promotions and new products that you may be interested in.

_Aggregate Information_  
Whenever you visit our website, our web server automatically collects and aggregates information in respect of your visit. This information includes URLs or domains of referring websites, browser type, operating system, the pages that you access and the date and time of your visit. In general this aggregate information will not identify you personally. If we do correlate such information to you, we will treat it in accordance with this Privacy Policy.

### 2\. Purposes for which we use Information

Information that you have provided to us may be used for the following purposes:

_Product Registration_  
Information you provide upon registration will be used to keep a record of your purchases and will assist us in providing assistance if you contact our customer support service. We will also use this information, upon your consent, to inform you of any upgrades, new products or promotions that may be of interest to you.

_Product Purchases_  
When you purchase products and services from us, we will use your information to process payment and provide you with technical assistance you require in respect to our products.

_Internal Analysis_  
We may use the information you provide us with for our own internal statistical and analytical purposes, to evaluate and profile customers, including customer preferences and purchasing trends, which we may use for marketing purposes and in respect of operations and development.

_Updating Information_  
We may use your contact information to verify information we have in our records is still correct and to add additional information to complete your profile.

### 3\. Sharing of Information with Third Parties

Information about our customers is an important part of our business, and we are not in the business of selling it to others. We share customer information only as described below and to ensure coordinated management of customers’ personal data with other subsidiaries controlled by Amazon.com.

_Outside Service Providers_  
We may use outside providers to perform functions on our behalf. Examples include: processing your payments for products and services, sending you email and newsletters, providing support and assistance related to our products and services, and providing customer service. We and our outside providers do however respect the applicable regulations, in particular those regarding the protection of personal data.

_Protection of IVONA and Others_  
We release account and other personal information when we believe release is appropriate to comply with the law, applicable judicial proceedings, or court order; enforce or apply our [Terms of Use](https://www.ivona.com/us/terms-of-use/) and other agreements; or protect the rights, property, or safety of IVONA, Amazon.com, other subsidiaries controlled by Amazon.com, any of our users, or others. This includes exchanging information with other companies and organizations for fraud protection and credit risk reduction. Obviously, however, this does not include selling, renting, sharing, or otherwise disclosing personally identifiable information from customers for commercial purposes in violation of the commitments set forth in this Privacy Policy.

_Third-Party Websites, Products & Services_  
Please be aware that this Privacy Policy does not cover the information practices exercised by other providers of products or services, advertisers, other websites or any other third party which may be involved in or linked to IVONA’s business. Your personal information may be subject to different privacy practices exercised by such providers, and IVONA is not responsible for the privacy practices exercised by any such provider. If you would like more information about the privacy practices of these providers and to know your choices about not having this information used by these companies, please review the privacy notices of these providers individually to learn more about how they handle privacy.

### 4\. Security

We use reasonable efforts to ensure that your information is stored and maintained in a secure environment. We have implemented procedures to ensure that your information is only made available to such designated IVONA staff as necessary to carry out the stated purposes that we have communicated to you.

_SSL Encryption_  
Order information received by IVONA’s website store, which may include credit card information, is encrypted using Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) software, which encrypts information you input.

### 5\. Cookies

We may make use of "cookies" on our website. A cookie is a small text file that can be placed and stored on your computer's hard drive and/or mobile device ("device") when you visit a website for record keeping purposes. A cookie itself is not designed or intended to read any information from a user's device (other than the contents of the cookie); rather, it is an identifier used by the website that originally placed it on your device's hard drive. The actual contents of the cookie information can be retrieved by the same server to identify the device and subsequently to customize, monitor, or regulate the use of a website based on information stored on the host server. Therefore, cookies only identify the user's device to the website which may correlate other information, including personally identifying information, with the cookie.

We use cookies to allow us to automate access and the data entry functions of our website, such as to correlate online ordering information for purchases you may make while at the website (if any), tailor our website to your preferences or interests, or customize promotions or marketing. In addition, cookies allow us to track use of our website to determine those areas which are useful or popular and those that are not, thereby enabling us to improve and update our website effectively.

Most web browsers can either alert you to the use of cookies or refuse to accept cookies entirely. If you are not sure how to do this or whether you have this option you should consult the information that accompanied your web browser. You should be aware that if you elect not to accept cookies, some parts of the website may not function properly or permit access.

In case you visit our website or use our products or services on a publicly accessible computer, e.g. in an internet cafe, please remember to delete cookies and history of the web browser.

You will be asked to give your consent to our use of cookies before your first access to the IVONA website when required by applicable law.

### 6\. Links

We may offer links from our website to other websites which may be hosted by our partners or by unrelated companies which we think may be of interest to you. Such websites are not governed by this Privacy Policy and IVONA makes no representation as to their practices for dealing with your personal information. We recommend that you check the privacy policy of any website at the beginning of your visit.

### 7\. Chat Rooms and Newsgroups

IVONA website may have chat rooms, newsgroups, or other forums which permit individuals to interact online. Any information you transmit online in such forums will be made public and IVONA cannot control nor is it responsible for the use any third parties may make of such information.

### 8\. Children

This website is a general audience website which is neither designed nor intended to collect personal information from children (persons under the age of 18). In order for us to ensure compliance with relevant regulations if you are under the age of 18 you should not provide any personal information to this website. We ask that parents supervise their children while online.

### 9\. Your Rights and Accuracy of Information

When you visit our website or use any of our products or services you provide your personal information voluntarily. We take reasonable steps to ensure that the information that we receive from you is accurate and kept up to date.

We respect your rights under applicable law. In particular, you have the right to access your information to verify the information that we have collected in respect of you. You may also have the right to request that your information be modified or deleted, including any changes to any consents that you may have given in respect of us contacting you about information that you receive from us. You may also ask at any time that your preferences as to the type of communications that you receive from us are modified in order to stop receiving them or to be added to our mailing list. We will endeavor to deal with all such requests for access and modifications in a timely manner. We will not be able to comply with requests in respect of information that we may have archived as part our business operations.

### 10\. Retention and Storage of Information

We will retain your information for the period necessary to fulfill the purposes outlined in this Privacy Policy unless a longer retention period is required or permitted by applicable regulations.

We may use the services of third party companies to physically collect and store your information on our behalf. Any such companies will have to comply with the terms of this Privacy Policy.

### 11\. Changes to this Privacy Policy

We may update this Privacy Policy from time to time in order to reflect our practices and provide greater protection for your information. Information collected by us will be dealt with in accordance with the provisions of this Privacy Policy which were in effect at the time of collection.

### 12\. Contact Us

Any requests for access to your information, modification of your information, withdrawal your consent for collecting your personal data or receive any communication from us or questions in respect of this Privacy Policy should be sent to [IVONA Customer Support](https://www.ivona.com/us/contact/customer-support/).
